Guide to the Felix S. Cohen Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Legal Career, 1931-1953; Series I; 29; (57 boxes)
  - INDIAN LAW SURVEY
    - Handbook of Federal Indian Law, Drafts, etc.
      - Draft and comments of chp. 9, Individual rights in tribal property; chp. 12, Indian education; chp. 25, Pueblos of New Mexico, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 247)
      - Draft outline of Indian Law (Box 14, Folder 248-49)
        See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1615
      - Draft chp. 3, miscellaneous pages, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 250)
      - Draft chp. 12, Indian education, 1939 Sep (Box 14, Folder 251)
      - Draft chp. 25, Pueblos, 1939 Sep (Box 14, Folder 252)
      - Drafts, Table of Cases, ca. 1940 (Box 14, Folder 253-55)
      - Drafts, Table of Cases, ca. 1940 (Box 15, Folder 256-57)
      - Index, 1940, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 258)
      - Index notes, 1941, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 259)
      - Analytical Index of Federal Indian Law
        See: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1616
      - Miscellaneous pages, 1934, 1938, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 260)
      - Handbook printing arrangements, 1940-45 (Box 15, Folder 261)
      - Index printing arrangements, 1941, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 262)
      - Correspondence regarding distribution, 1939-49 (Box 15, Folder 263-69)
      - Correspondence regarding distribution, 1939-49 (Box 16, Folder 270-76)
      - Comments, 1939-41 (Box 16, Folder 277-80)
      - Comments - 2nd Edition, 1942-43 (Box 16, Folder 281)
      - Corrections, 1937-41, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 282)
      - Corrections second edition, 1941-46 (Box 16, Folder 283)
      - Handbook (2d ed.) - Review copies, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 284)
      - Review 1945 edition in Yale Law Journal, 1945 Mar (Box 16, Folder 285)
      - Criticisms, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 286)
      - Publicity, 1941-42 (Box 16, Folder 287-88)
      - Publicity, 1943-45 (Box 17, Folder 289)
    - Subject Files
      - Bureau of Indian Affairs, 1935, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 290)
      - Dept. of Justice Style and Citation Manual for the Lands Division, 1939 Mar (Box 17, Folder 291)
      - Dept. of Justice telephone directory, 1938-39 (Box 17, Folder 292)
      - Eminent domain book, sections relating to Indians (Box 17, Folder 293)
      - Indian constitutions and charters, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 294)
      - Indian Field Service regulations, ca. 1937 (Box 17, Folder 295)
      - Indian School Service administrative set-up, ca. 1937 (Box 17, Folder 296)
      - Water law cases, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 297)
      - Yakima Indians proceedings, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 298)
      - Miscellaneous clippings, 1938, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 299)
      - Miscellaneous material, 1930-42, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 300-03)
        See also: BSD, folder 1604
  - ALASKA: NATURAL RESOURCES AND NATIVE AFFAIRS
    This subseries documents Cohen's work for the Interior Department on Alaskan Indian issues, concerning natural resources, and aboriginal rights. Some of these files were used and augmented by Cohen while in private practice.
    - Alaskan Development Act, 1941, 1941, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 304)
    - Alaskan Development Act, 1941, 1941-46 (Box 18, Folder 305-06)
    - Follow-up on final report, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 307)
    - Parmelee, [Maurice, economic consultant], 1939-44 (Box 18, Folder 308-09)
    - Alaska report, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 310-15)
    - Alaska report, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 316)
    - Alaska bill publicity, 1936-42, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 317-23)
      See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1637
    - Revision of Alaska report, 1939-40 (Box 19, Folder 324-26)
    - Dr. Weiss - Alaska studies, 1939-46 (Box 19, Folder 327-29)
    - [Alaska bill], 1940, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 330-31)
    - George W. Folta, [Counsel at Large, Dept. of Interior, Juneau Office], 1940-44 (Box 19, Folder 332)
    - Alaska - fishery hearings, 1942-43 (Box 19, Folder 333)
    - Alaska - fishery hearings, 1944 Jan-Jun (Box 19, Folder 334)
    - Alaska Trip, June 4 - July 9, 1944, 1944 Jun-Jul (Box 19, Folder 335)
    - Alaska - fishery hearings, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 336-40)
    - Alaska - fishery hearings, 1945, 1944-46 (Box 20, Folder 341-42)
    - Alaska - publicity, 1944-45 (Box 20, Folder 343)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1617, Box 101, folder 1636
    - Alaska fisheries - regulations 1946, 1941-47 (Box 20, Folder 344-46)
    - Alaska fisheries - regulations 1946 (Box 21, Folder 347-50)
    - Alaskan economic memo, ca. 1946 (Box 21, Folder 351)
    - Hydaburg, etc., trapsites, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 352)
    - Alaska fisheries bills, 1942-44, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 353-58)
    - Indian Office - briefs in Alaska fishery hearings, 1945, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 359-60)
    - Alaska - proposed policy statements, 1942-47 (Box 21, Folder 361-62)
    - Statement on Alaskan native rights, 1944, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 363)
    - Bibliography of American possessions - Alaska, 1940-41 (Box 22, Folder 364)
    - Alaska legislation - early drafts, 1939, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 365)
    - Miller case, 1947-48, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 366)
    - Alaska native hunting and fishing rights, 1944, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 367)
    - Alaska aboriginal hearings, 1944-47 (Box 22, Folder 368-69)
    - Alaska fish trap bill, 1938-48, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 370)
    - Alaska salmon trap bill - S. 1446; H.R. 3859 (Box 22, Folder 371)
    - Hydaburg decision, 1944-45 (Box 22, Folder 372-73)
    - Alaska - 1941-42-43, 1940-47 (Box 23, Folder 374-75)
    - Alaska - 1945, 1944-46 (Box 23, Folder 376)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1618
    - Alaska - 1946, 1945-46 (Box 23, Folder 377)
    - Alaska - General, 1945-46 (Box 23, Folder 378)
    - Alaska: Miscellaneous, 1946-47 (Box 23, Folder 379)
    - Alaska - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 23, Folder 380)
    - Alaska fisheries opinions, 1940-42 (Box 23, Folder 381-83)
    - Indian fish traps, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 384)
    - Alaska Native Brotherhood, 1943-45 (Box 23, Folder 385-87)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1619
    - Hearings on S. 3577 [Alaskan Settlement & Development]
      - [Notes, drafts, correspondence], 1939-40 (Box 23, Folder 388-91)
      - [Notes, drafts, correspondence] (Box 24, Folder 392)
      - [ Report of Proceedings. Hearings held before Subcommittee of the Committee on Territories and Insular Affairs ], 1940 May 13 (Box 24, Folder 393)
      - Alaska fishermen's citizenship case, 1941 (Box 24, Folder 394)
      - Kendi development bill, 1940 (Box 24, Folder 395)
      - 1941 Alaska bill, 1939-41 (Box 24, Folder 396)
      - Alaska land bill, 1940-41 (Box 24, Folder 397)
      - [Letters to legislators introducing Alaskan development bill], 1939-40 (Box 24, Folder 398)
    - Testimony on S. J. Res. 162, 1945-48 (Box 24, Folder 399-402)
    - Alaska organization, 1936-37 (Box 24, Folder 403)
    - Alaskan Rural Rehabilitation Corporation, 1939, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 404)
    - Alaska - economic possibilities, 1938-39 (Box 24, Folder 405)
    - Committee [on Alaska] - meetings, etc., 1937-39, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 406-08)
    - Alaskan fish trap legislation, 1944-47 (Box 25, Folder 409-11)
    - Alaskan fish trap legislation, 1948, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 412)
    - Alaska articles - FSC, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 413)
    - Correspondence re: Alaska bill, 1939, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 414)
    - Special Alaska development bills, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 415)
    - Alaska legislation, 1939-40 (Box 25, Folder 416-17)
    - Alaska legislation, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 418)
    - Current Alaska Material
      The following files were arranged by Cohen under the title "Current Alaska Material." If he used the title to designate files he was currently using, it may reflect his legal interests just prior to his death.
      - Tongass timber legislation, 1947-48, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 419-22)
      - Karluk - Petition for Certiorari, 1948 Feb 13 (Box 26, Folder 423)
      - Karluk - general, 1946-50, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 424-28)
      - Karluk - litigation, 1944, 1946 (Box 26, Folder 429)
      - Karluk - litigation, 1947-50, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 430-32)
        See also: BSD, folder 1605
      - Alaska - Shungnak [Reservation], 1947 (Box 27, Folder 433)
    - Alaskan towns - AL, 1947-49, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 434)
    - Kake timber, 1947-48 (Box 27, Folder 435)
    - Alaska - [Cohen's] letter to [Washington] Post on Timber Road (Box 27, Folder 436)
      - Appropriations, 1949
    - Metlakatla [Indian Community] and Annette Islands Reserve, 1940-53 (Box 27, Folder 437)
    - Alaska general, 1947-50 (Box 27, Folder 438)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1620
    - Alaska development, 1939-40 (Box 27, Folder 439-40)
    - Alaska reservations - general, 1937-47 (Box 27, Folder 441-42)
    - Alaska reservations - general, 1949-51, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 443-44)
      See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1621
    - Alaska land grab, 1949-49 (Box 28, Folder 445)
    - Alaska trip, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 446)
    - Alaska land claims bills, 1943-47, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 447-49)
    - Alaska fishing case (Paul case) and condemnation case, 1942-45, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 450-52)
    - Alaska land [- development] settlement bill (Box 28, Folder 453)
    - Alaska publicity: 1948, 1943-48, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 454-55)
    - Alaska development program: 1946, 1944-47, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 456-57)
      See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1638
    - Alaska - miscellaneous, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 458)
    - Alaska - miscellaneous, 1939-40 (Box 29, Folder 459-65)
    - Tlingit - Haida reading, 1947-48 (Box 29, Folder 466)
    - Tlingit - Haida, 1941-53, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 467-68)
    - Tlingit - Haida, 1939-48, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 469-73)
    - Tlingit - Haida [draft memorandum of law, Possessory Rights of Tlingit and Haida Indians], 1939-48, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 474-77)
  - TERRITORIES
    This subseries contains Cohen's Interior files concerning issues involving United States territories.
    See also: Box 51, folders 786, 788
    - Territories and island possessions, 1940-47, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 478-79)
    - Territories - routine - 1937-39, 1938 (Box 30, Folder 480)
    - Territories - routine - 1940 (Box 30, Folder 481)
    - Territories - routine - 1941 (Box 30, Folder 482)
    - Territories - general, 1942-46, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 483-84)
    - Immigration to territories, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 485)
    - Civil Aeronautics Board, 1944-45 (Box 31, Folder 486)
    - Guam, 1946-49 (Box 31, Folder 487-90)
    - Hawaii, 1942-43, 1946 (Box 31, Folder 491-93)
    - Philippine Islands
      - Philippine Sugar Association, 1945-46 (Box 31, Folder 494)
      - ["Philippine Islands: Economic Conference," press release by the Department of State], 1937 Jan 2 (Box 31, Folder 495)
    - Puerto Rico
      - Newspaper Clippings - "Science and Politics in Plans for Puerto Rico" (Box 31, Folder 496)
      - Human - natural resources, 1946-48, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 497-99)
        See also: BSD, folder 1606
      - Puerto Rico paper, 1947, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 500)
      - PR 1934 on [articles and notes by Cohen and research material], 1939-48 (Box 32, Folder 501-04)
        See also: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1622
      - Fortas contract, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 505)
      - Agricultural Company case - affidavits, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 506)
      - Agricultural Company case, Suarez- Martinez v. Tugwell: clippings, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 507)
        See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1639
      - Agricultural Company case briefs, [1946] (Box 32, Folder 508-09)
      - Puerto Rico trip: miscellaneous (Feb. 1946) (Box 32, Folder 510)
      - Puerto Rico legislation, 1946, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 511)
      - Puerto Rico 1946: misc. litigation, 1944-46 (Box 33, Folder 512-15)
      - PR Agricultural Co. case 1946 - pleadings, etc. (Box 33, Folder 516)
      - Complete inventory of housing properties to be taken over by Puerto Rico Housing Authority, 1945-46, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 517)
      - Puerto Rico legislation, 1937-43, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 518)
      - Puerto Rico Water Resources Auth[ority], 1941-42 (Box 33, Folder 519)
      - Puerto Rico - general, 1941-51 (Box 33, Folder 520-22)
      - Puerto Rico hearings - House and Senate, 1942-43 (Box 34, Folder 523)
      - Puerto Rico - sugar, 1943-45, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 524-27)
      - Puerto Rico - self-government (drafts, duplicates, notes, miscellaneous papers), 1943, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 528)
      - Puerto Rico legislation, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 529)
      - Puerto Rico - Lafayette Cooperatives, 1937, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 530)
      - Puerto Rico - education, 1937 (Box 34, Folder 531)
      - ["Gross Product of Puerto Rico, 1944-46"], [1946] (Box 34, Folder 532)
      - Puerto Rico ["Legislative Reorganization in Puerto Rico: A Call and a Program"], 1946 (Box 34, Folder 533)
    - Virgin Islands
      - Virgin Islands ["The First Negro Governor," Saturday Evening Post ]
        See: Oversize, Box 100, folder 1623
      - James A. Bough - Territories - V.I., 1941 (Box 34, Folder 534)
      - Brodhurst case - V.I., 1944 (Box 34, Folder 535)
      - Correspondence - V.I., 1940-41 (Box 34, Folder 536)
      - Draft regulations - V.I. - admission of aliens to V.I., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 537)
      - Virgin Islands, 1939-40 (Box 34, Folder 538)
      - Virgin Islands, 1940 (Box 35, Folder 539-40)
      - Hastie, Wm. H., 1948-49 (Box 35, Folder 541)
      - V.I. proclamations, etc., 1940, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 542)
      - Supplementary opinions (memos) on proclamation, 1940, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 543)
      - V.I. refuge, 1939-41, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 544-50)
      - Supplementary V.I. memo, 1940, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 551-52)
      - Virgin Islands - refugees, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 553-54)
      - V.I. - publicity, 1940 (Box 36, Folder 555)
      - V.I. refuge - Dec 1940 - legal issues, ca. 1940 (Box 36, Folder 556-58)
      - Virgin Islands - sent to Secretary, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 559-61)
      - Report to Secretary, Nov 18 - Virgin Islands, 1940 Nov (Box 36, Folder 562)
      - Virgin Islands alien defense workers, 1941 (Box 36, Folder 563-64)
      - V.I. Refuge - May 1941, 1940-41, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 565-68)
      - Virgin Islands refuge opinion, 1940 (Box 37, Folder 569)
  - SOLICITOR'S OFFICE RECORDS
    - Aliens - Immigrants
      - Regulations - aliens, 1939-40 (Box 37, Folder 570)
      - Alien problems, 1941-42 (Box 37, Folder 571)
      - Wriedt case, 1940-41 (Box 37, Folder 572-73)
      - Immigration - gen'l immigration, 1940-41 (Box 37, Folder 574)
    - Atomic Energy
      See also: Box 71, folders 1134-35
      - Atomic Energy, 1945-46 Jan (Box 37, Folder 575-76)
        See also: BSD, folder 1607
      - Atomic Energy, 1946-52, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 577-83)
      - [Congressional Investigation into the United States Atomic Energy Project: publication of Hearings], 1949 (Box 38, Folder 584-85)
    - Patents
      - Patent issues, 1945-46 (Box 39, Folder 586-93)
    - Public Lands and Natural Resources
      - Park regulations, 1939-41 (Box 39, Folder 594)
      - Land policies - departmental, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 595-96)
      - General departmental - public lands investigation, 1935-44 (Box 39, Folder 597)
      - Surplus property, 1944-46 (Box 39, Folder 598)
      - Surplus property [disposal of property in Alaska], 1946-47 (Box 39, Folder 599)
      - Property Acquisition Division, 1944-47 (Box 39, Folder 600)
      - Parks and conservation, 1933-35 (Box 39, Folder 601-02)
      - Parks and conservation, 1936-46 (Box 40, Folder 603-04)
        See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1640
      - Nat[iona]l Capital Parks - C[hesapeake] & O[hio] Canal Company, 1941, 1946 (Box 40, Folder 605)
      - Coordinator of Fisheries [salmon canning industry, Pilchard Order], 1943-46 (Box 40, Folder 606)
    - Reclamation
      - [Bureau of Reclamation - engineering projects Yangtze River, Palestine, and American River projects], 1945-46 (Box 40, Folder 607)
      - ["Rebuilding the Rio Grande" by Ward Shepard], 1945 Apr (Box 40, Folder 608)
      - Rio Grande Committee, 1942-46 (Box 40, Folder 609)
    - Spanish Embargo of 1937
      - Cases [regarding 1937 resolutions on the Spanish embargo], ca. 1937 (Box 40, Folder 610)
      - Legislative history [of joint resolutions on the Spanish embargo], ca. 1937-38 (Box 40, Folder 611)
      - Greeley [Helen Hoy, material on joint resolution prepared for Solicitor Margold], 1938-39 (Box 40, Folder 612-13)
      - First draft [of memorandum for the Secretary regarding legal status of Spanish embargo] (Box 40, Folder 614)
      - [Draft of memorandum] (Box 41, Folder 615)
      - Repeal of embargo, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 616)
      - Spain - misc., 1936-38 (Box 41, Folder 617)
      - Lawyers Committee brief [regarding president's power to lift embargo], ca. 1938-39 (Box 41, Folder 618)
      - Lawyers Committee [on American relations with Spain], 1938-39, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 619-22)
      - Lawyers Committee [on American Relations with Spain], 1938-39, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 623-25)
      - Final draft [of memorandum for Secretary regarding embargo and Lawyers Committee Brief], 1939 Feb (Box 41, Folder 626)
    - Other Issues
      - October 1940 [Wilkie - Roosevelt contest], 1940-41, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 627)
      - Conference on Scientific Spirit and Democratic Faith, 1944-45 (Box 42, Folder 628)
      - Council Against Intolerance in America, 1939-41 (Box 42, Folder 629)
      - Conscription report [by Institute of Living Law], 1940 (Box 42, Folder 630-31)
      - Legislation - soldiers's voting, 1942 (Box 42, Folder 632)
      - Post-war planning [American plans for Germany], 1942-44 (Box 42, Folder 633)
      - Restrictive racial covenants (Pearce v. Crocker), 1947 (Box 42, Folder 634)
      - Grace L. Dent (Personal Files) [Bureau of Mines - Compliance Order re: explosives], [1943?] (Box 42, Folder 635)
      - Mr. Cohen work file - Interior Dept, 1946-47 (Box 42, Folder 636-39)
    - Annual Reports and Correspondence
      - Annual report [of the Office of the Solicitor] 1942-43, 1942-44 (Box 42, Folder 640)
      - Annual Report [of the Office of the Solicitor] 1946 (Box 42, Folder 641)
      - Solicitor's office reports, 1946-47 (Box 43, Folder 642-43)
      - Correspondence, 1934-37 (Box 43, Folder 644-48)
      - Correspondence, 1937-40 (Box 43, Folder 649-52)
      - Misc[ellaneous Interior correspondence and memos], 1941 (Box 43, Folder 653)
      - Miscellaneous [Interior correspondence and memos], 1944-47 (Box 43, Folder 654-56)
      - [Miscellaneous Interior correspondence and memos], 1947-48, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 657)
      - Department - general [correspondence and office memoranda], 1941-43 (Box 44, Folder 658-60)
      - Department - general [correspondence and office memoranda], 1944-45, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 661-67)
      - Secretary of the Interior [memos from Solicitor], 1941-43 (Box 44, Folder 668)
      - Solicitor's opinions and administrative findings, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 669-71)
      - Solicitor's opinions and administrative findings, 1943-46 (Box 45, Folder 672-79)
      - Solicitor's opinions - general [and administrative findings], 1947 (Box 45, Folder 680-83)
      - Miscellaneous solicitor's opinions, 1934-35 (Box 45, Folder 684)
      - Miscellaneous solicitor's opinions, 1936-38 (Box 46, Folder 685)
      - Solicitor's memoranda, 1946-47 (Box 46, Folder 686)
      - [Solicitor's memos - Status of Indian surplus lands and personnel memo], 1947 (Box 46, Folder 687)
      - Memos, decisions, opinions, etc. listed with Dept of Interior Law Library [bimonthly reports], 1946-47 (Box 46, Folder 688-89)
      - Department of Interior - press releases, 1949-50 (Box 46, Folder 690)
      - Department of Interior - press releases, 1949-52 (Box 46, Folder 691)
      - Interior Department - regulations, etc., 1938-50, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 692-93)
      - Forms [memos re: paperwork], 1946-47 (Box 46, Folder 694)
      - Expenses [travel], 1934-43 (Box 46, Folder 695-99)
      - Expenses [travel], 1944-47, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 700-02)
      - [Cohen's] travel, 1946-47 (Box 47, Folder 703)
      - Budget - 1947, 1947-48, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 704-05)
    - Structure of Interior - Relations with other Units
      - Delegation of power [within Interior], 1941-46, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 706-07)
      - Office organization, 1941-44, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 708-10)
        See also: BSD, folder 1608
      - Budget survey [recommendations for structure of legal work in Interior Dept.], 1940, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 711)
        See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1641
      - Coordination Committee [integration of departmental programs], 1946-47 (Box 47, Folder 712-13)
      - Agency Records
        - Office of Propaganda Investigation, 1939-41 (Box 47, Folder 714)
        - Board of Appeals, 1940-46 (Box 48, Folder 715-16)
        - Mines Division, 1940-45 (Box 48, Folder 717)
        - Public Lands Division, 1944-47 (Box 48, Folder 718)
        - Justice Dept, 1945-47 (Box 48, Folder 719)
        - Conservation Division, 1944-47 (Box 48, Folder 720)
        - Fish and Wildlife Service, 1941-47 (Box 48, Folder 721-22)
        - Legislative Division, 1944-46 (Box 48, Folder 723-24)
        - Legislative Division, 1947, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 725-26)
        - Power Division, 1945-46 (Box 48, Folder 727)
    - Personnel Files
      - [Eugenie] Tetons matter etc. [personnel matters], 1939-42 (Box 48, Folder 728)
      - Employee investigations, 1941-43 (Box 49, Folder 729)
      - (1) Practice before department (2) Testimony of officials, 1942-47 (Box 49, Folder 730)
      - Legality of employment of former government employees, 1944, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 731)
      - Attorney recruitment, 1944-45, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 732-33)
      - Personnel pending, 1940-47 (Box 49, Folder 734)
      - In-service training, 1944-46 (Box 49, Folder 735)
      - Legal jobs report, 1941-42 (Box 49, Folder 736)
      - Personnel - interior, 1945-47 (Box 49, Folder 737)
      - Representation before department, 1945 Nov 9 (Box 49, Folder 738)
      - Ward Shepard, 1944 (Box 49, Folder 739)
      - Official Status - Felix S. Cohen, Department of Interior, 1933-39 (Box 49, Folder 740-43)
        See also: Oversize, Box 101, folder 1642
      - Official Status - Felix S. Cohen, Department of Interior, 1940-48, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 744-45)
  - PRIVATE PRACTICE OFFICE RECORDS
    This section contains material from Cohen's private practice. Eventually Cohen's office became the Washington, D.C. branch of the New York law firm, Riegelman, Strasser, Schwarz and Spiegelberg. Additional files with material from this period can be found in the previous topical subsections of this series. The files have been arranged alphabetically by Cohen's folder titles, usually by name of client or legal associate.
    - 1948 daily publications digest (Box 50, Folder 746)
    - 1948 daily publications digest (Box 50, Folder 747-49)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1947-51 (Box 50, Folder 750-57)
    - Cavanaugh, Pansy [Blackfeet Tribal Council], 1950 (Box 50, Folder 758)
    - Chief, Elizabeth, 1949-50 (Box 50, Folder 759)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1949-50 (Box 50, Folder 760)
    - Consultative Council of Jewish Organizations, 1948-49 (Box 50, Folder 761-66)
    - Consultative Council of Jewish Organizations, 1949-50 (Box 51, Folder 767-71)
    - Cowher, Edward C., 1949 Sept 17 (Box 51, Folder 772)
    - Dodge, Thomas H. [superintendent Truxton Canaon Agency, Hualapai Indians], 1948 (Box 51, Folder 773)
    - Firethunder, William [President Oglala Sioux Tribal Council], 1948 (Box 51, Folder 774)
    - Horn, Frances Lopinsky [lawyer of Curry, [H.] Cohen & Bingham], 1948-49 (Box 51, Folder 775)
    - Institute of Ethnic Affairs, 1944-53, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 776-88)
    - Institute of Ethnic Affairs, 1945, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 789)
    - Ketter, David, 1949 (Box 52, Folder 790)